[The Heir]
[Episode 37]
Tian family and Li family,
hear the verdict.
The evidence of the Tians'
illicit foreign trade is conclusive.
But regarding who the mastermind is
and what the charges are,
we still need further judgment.
Except for Tian Ronghua alone,
Tian Benchang,
Tian Huai'an,
Tian Bensheng,
Wang Xiu,
Wu Xin,
and 3 accomplices
of the Tian family's illicit foreign trade
shall all be remanded in custody
to await trial!
The Li family's illicit foreign trade is
indeed a false accusation made
by Wu Xin at the Tians' instigation.
It is completely
fabricated.
All members of the Li family
shall be released today.
-Thank you, Your Excellency.
Court is adjourned.
Great!
Take it slow, Uncle Jingdong.
[Huizhou Prefecture Office]
Okay.
Eighth Uncle.
Zhen.
Uncle Jingdong.
Grandfather.
Zhen, what's the result?
Please rest assured.
The Li family has finally
been cleared of the false charges.
Eldest Aunt, Third Aunt,
and Zhengshen
will also be released.
Don't worry, everything is fine now.
Then let's wait here.
We'll wait for them to come out
and go home together.
Ronghua,
go home with us later.
Zhen,
can you go
to the Chen Ink Workshop with me?
Third Grandfather.
Girl, you really are...
Uncle Junshan.
Zhen.
Ronghua
has something to say to you.
Third Grandfather,
Uncle Junshan,
during the previous Tribute Ink selection,
I was foolish to ask Qing He to step in,
causing the Chen family
to lose the tribute ink contract
and disrupting the rules
of the Huizhou ink industry.
Yet the peers in the Hui Ink industry
still saved me today.
I feel extremely ashamed.
I know my sins are unforgivable.
Whether you want to beat me
or scold me, Third Grandfather,
I will have no complaints.
Third Grandfather,
the Tian family's crimes were made public
all thanks to Ronghua placing
righteousness above family loyalty.
Although the Tian family is notorious
for the crimes they committed,
I can guarantee
that Ronghua is not cut
from the same cloth as them.
The mistake has been made.
Regret won't change anything.
You can't change what's already happened.
You're right, Third Grandfather.
I dare not ask for forgiveness.
But I promise,
if Qing He falls one day,
I will turn myself in, testify,
and restore the Chen family's reputation.
Before that day comes,
I promise I will not leave Huizhou,
not even by a single step.
You clarified this matter
in front of everyone
in the ink industry and Prefect He,
without shifting the blame
or making any excuses.
And you even promise
to turn yourself in and testify.
It's truly not easy.
Also, my father
and brothers were engaged
in illicit foreign trade.
They will definitely be convicted.
After that, I will disband
the Tian Ink Workshop,
quit the ink industry,
and never make ink again.
I will also write down every detail
of all the crimes
that the Tian family has committed
and submit it to the Literary Association
for preservation,
so this record of crimes
can warn future generations
as a permanent admonition.
You are having the Tian family
remembered forever as a shame
in the Huizhou ink industry.
It should be like this,
and should have been so long ago.
The title of Tribute Ink is
the lifelong pursuit of any ink maker.
But for family honor
and personal benefits,
I trampled on it.
The Tian family even used the name
of Tribute Ink to cause trouble
and bring about disasters,
doing countless terrible things.
We've hurt you,
Third Grandfather,
Uncle Junshan, and so many people
in the Hui Ink industry.
There's no way
we can fully make up for it.
How I wish
I could do more
to make amends.
Third Grandfather.
You two girls
have one thing in common.
At such a young age,
you are both strong enough
to shoulder responsibilities.
Stand up now.
Miss Tian,
you had been away
from Huizhou for too long.
Try the She County's Lotus Tea I brewed.
This is the taste from your hometown.
What are you waiting for?
Go ahead.
Third Grandfather has forgiven you.
Go ahead!
Thank you, Third Grandfather.
Give it a try.
How is it?
Zhen,
it's been such a long day.
I feel
it's longer than any day before.
So many things have happened,
and the sun is finally going to set.
Yes.
When the sun rises tomorrow,
everything that happened today
will be in the past
and be gone forever.
Ronghua,
come home with me.
If you think City Gate Lane is
too crowded,
you can live in my New Li Ink Workshop.
Zhen.
Do you still remember
the employment letter
I gave you in Nanjing?
I've wanted to hire you as an accountant
at my New Li Ink Workshop.
You wouldn't live for free.
You have to work for me, understand?
What?
Are you refusing it
because you have quit
your old profession for a long time
and gotten rusty?
Zhen.
I want to show you something.
Well...
You still keep
this abacus bead?
Yes, of course.
Ronghua,
I know
when you gave me
this abacus bead back then,
you were entrusting me with the life
that you couldn't get to live.
Today,
I'm returning it to its owner.
Ronghua,
the past is
in the past.
From now on,
we'll start anew.
Zhen,
thank you.
Accepting this abacus bead
means you have agreed
to be the accountant
at my New Li Ink Workshop.
Let's go, dear accountant.
Sister Cuiqiao!
Cuiqiao!
Zhen.
Is there any reply
from the Princess's Mansion?
My men rode fast to deliver your letter
and waited there for a day and a night.
Here is the reply.
Did anything happen
at the Nanjing Garrison Commander's Manor?
Don't worry.
Wu Ru hasn't taken any action yet.
The letter says that
the news about the Tian family's
illicit foreign trade
has spread in Nanjing.
The Princess has personally intervened
and warned Commander Wu.
Commander Wu is in hot water himself
and cannot shield the Tian family anymore.
The letter also says that
the Directorate of Ceremony has blocked
the impeachment memorial
against Marshal Qi.
Really?
Check it out.
For real?
This is wonderful.
Wenqian
finally got a silver lining.
Marshal Qi
can also breathe a sigh of relief.
Now, Commander Wu is tied up
covering up for himself,
trying to save his own skin.
So this is
the perfect time for us
to completely bring down Tian Benchang.
Do you have any plans, then?
Although the Tian Mansion
and Tian Ink Workshop
have been seized,
since they were
put into prison all of a sudden,
I think there might still be some clues
that they didn't have time to clean up,
and that would be
a chance for us.
So, we must try to thoroughly
look into the Tian family again.
Officer Zhang!
Mr. Zhang!
Shut up! What are you yelling about?
Officer,
it's been days.
Why hasn't my second brother been
sentenced for the illicit foreign trade?
Is there any news from outside?
Mr. Zhang, you're finally here!
Mr. Zhang.
Open the door.
Mr. Zhang,
is there any letter from Nanjing?
Eldest Young Master Tian,
let me be honest with you.
Since your Tians were imprisoned,
there hasn't been a single message from
the Nanjing Garrison Commander's Manor.
Didn't you always claim
that Commander Wu was
on good terms with you
and would definitely
protect the Tian family?
Did you make all that up in your head?
Mr. Zhang, could you please
get me a writing brush and some paper?
Don't forget,
you received
quite a lot of money from me before.
If you push me too hard,
I'll spill everything in court.
Mr. Zhang,
please send this letter
to the Nanjing Garrison Commander's Manor
and make sure you give it
to Commander Wu personally.
He will surely help us out
once he sees this letter.
Prefect He is dead set on getting
to the bottom of your Tian family's
illicit foreign trade.
The past few days, he's been
dispatching people to investigate
the refugees making ink for your family.
If someone gives you away,
you'll be as good as dead.
Do not drag me down with you
when that happens.
Mr. Zhang,
so long as you help me
deliver this letter,
you'll be my savior.
I still have some money
deposited in Nanjing.
Take this receipt and withdraw it.
Consider it my gift for you.
When I get out of here one day,
I will never forget your kindness.
Is it clean money?
Clean, absolutely clean.
Ronghua, let's go...
Ronghua,
I can do the search on my own.
How about this?
You go back to New Li Ink Workshop
and wait for me there, okay?
I'll search with you.
I know where everything is
kept here better than you do.
You told me before
that facing the past
and exposing old scars
is the first step to a new beginning.
I also want to see the truest side
of my home,
so I can say goodbye
to it properly.
Ronghua, you're the bravest person
in the world.
Then let's do it together.
Let's go.
You're drinking?
Hi, Mr. Zhang.
W-Who is this?
A newcomer.
Take your time, sir.
Okay.
Who are you?
[Nanjing Garrison Commander's Manor]
You're from
the Nanjing Garrison Commander's Manor?
What did Commander Wu say?
Where is that thing you mentioned?
If I tell you now,
can I get out of here?
Help me out of here.
If you don't tell me,
I'll kill you right away.
Help me out of here,
and I will definitely hand over
the account book exactly as it is to you.
Otherwise, no one will get away with it!
Officer Zhang.
Officer Zhang!
Sir.
What's going on?
Zhen.
Zhen?
Zhen,
we've searched everywhere.
If there was really something important,
wouldn't Benchang
have hidden it somewhere else?
It is possible.
But I've always had a doubt.
At the critical moment
the other day, Tian Benchang
actually took out
the documents of illicit foreign trade
and shifted all the blame
onto your second brother.
So I guess
he was always wary
and on guard.
Therefore, he must have
put those documents
somewhere he could easily access.
That means we can't miss
a single corner
in the entire Tian Residence.
Let's keep searching.
If what you say is true,
then these things
must have been stored
where others wouldn't easily look through.
Ronghua.
What's that?
This is the scroll of a ritual poem
that Benchang humbly
asked Sage Qing He to write in person.
Ever since our family
got this scroll of the ritual poem,
he had cherished it like a treasure.
Not only did he mount
and frame it himself,
but he also specially hung it
in the study.
Although Sage Qing He got into trouble,
he hasn't completely fallen
from power.
The officers were probably afraid of him,
so they didn't dare to touch his thing.
The antiques and paintings in our house
have all been searched by the officers.
But only this scroll of the ritual poem
seems untouched.
Wait.
There's something inside.
Take it down.
Okay.
See?
Ronghua, don't tear it.
What's there to be afraid of?
This place is still
beyond Sage Qing He's reach right now.
How much pain did he bring to your family
and Third Master Chen back then?
Since I introduced this person here,
I should be the one
to end this evil trend with my own hands.
Take it slow. Be careful.
A travel permit?
[Travel Permit: An official travel document
issued by the Ming government]
Lu Wei,
[for people to prove their identity
during long journeys.]
a merchant from Fujian.
So,
why did Tian Benchang
go to such great lengths
to hide a travel permit?
Manager Zhen, Miss Tian,
are you still inside?
Bad news! Tian Benchang...
He's escaped from prison!
Let me in!
I want to see Lord He.
Let her in.
Your Excellency, Tian Benchang...
Li Zhen, hold on.
You go on.
Your Excellency,
Officer Zhang
brought a stranger over tonight.
I was just about to go take a closer look,
a-and that man just knocked me out.
Zhang Guang,
I can't believe you dared to help someone
escape from prison!
M-My Lord,
I know nothing.
That person knocked me out.
And I just
woke up to this state.
What is that person's name and background?
I-I don't know his name.
H-He seems to be...
I think he... I think...
Out with it!
Yes...
I think he's from
the Nanjing Garrison Commander's Manor.
I once asked someone to help
Tian Benchang send a letter to the Nanjing
Garrison Commander's Manor.
Soon after, that person came,
saying he wanted to see Tian Benchang.
Your Excellency,
Commander Wu
had been ignoring the Tian family.
But his man took such a risk tonight
to get Tian Benchang out of jail.
There must be a reason behind it.
I guess
Tian Benchang must have
gotten something on Commander Wu,
blackmailing Commander Wu to help him out.
Tell me
what that letter said.
It said... It said...
Right,
an account book.
Yes, it said there was an account book
that Commander Wu wanted.
But Tian Benchang said
he would only offer it after he broke out.
Bring the prisoner,
Tian Bensheng, over here.
Tian Bensheng,
where is Tian Benchang?
If he really gets away,
you'll be the one taking the death penalty
for illicit foreign trade.
Try your best to recall
where that account book is!
I have no idea, Your Excellency.
I've confessed everything
I know about our family.
I've never even heard
of the account book you mentioned.
Tian Benchang didn't tell me everything.
My father
only saw me as a fool.
I don't know anything else.
I really don't know anything else.
Your Excellency,
I would like to see Tian Huai'an.
Perhaps right now, besides Tian Benchang,
only Tian Huai'an knows
where this account book is.
Well...
[Travel Permit]
Your Excellency,
it's hard to travel at night.
Tian Benchang couldn't have gone far.
It'll be too late
if we delay any longer.
I'm begging you.
Please let me give it a try.
Alright.
Thank you, Your Excellency.
How much further is it?
It's right in the woods ahead.
Sir,
I haven't been here in a while.
I think I have forgotten the way.
Maybe we should go that way.
Where exactly is that place?
Sir,
if you put this sword away,
maybe I'll start remembering it.
This place is so desolate
that no carriages can pass,
and no one is around.
I couldn't escape even if I had wings.
Since you promised me
that you'd let me go
once you get the account book,
I have no reason to play tricks with you.
Sir!
Sir,
could you lend me
your token?
What do you need the token for?
I am penniless now,
and I can't go back home
to get my travel permit.
With this token,
I can at least enter a city somewhere else
and settle down.
You can worry about the future
after you hand over the item.
Thank you.
Master Tian.
Madam Tian.
Why are you here?
Master Tian,
that day in court,
you didn't mention anything
about Tian Benchang
and put all the blame on Tian Bensheng.
You must have believed that
sacrificing Tian Bensheng alone
would leave the Tian family a way out.
Indeed,
as stupid
and incompetent as Tian Bensheng is,
abandoning him is fine.
As long as you can save your eldest son,
the Tian family
still stands a chance,
right?
I don't get
a single thing you are saying.
I came here today
just to inform you both that Tian Benchang
has escaped from prison.
What?
He's escaped from prison?
Just last night,
someone sneaked into the prison
and got him out of here.
Don't listen to her nonsense.
He didn't escape.
He must have been released.
D-Don't listen to her nonsense.
I didn't want to give this to you,
but at this point...
Master Tian,
check this out.
Do you recognize the words on it?
This was found inside the scroll
of the ritual poem
in Tian Benchang's study.
It seems that Tian Benchang
left himself a way out long ago.
With this travel permit,
he can change his name
and start anew.
But what a pity.
There is only one travel permit,
with no others.
What is this travel permit about, Darling?
What exactly does Zhen mean by this?
Madam Tian,
do you still not understand?
Tian Benchang could even abandon
and make use of his own sister.
What else can't he let go of?
Darling,
Benchang won't leave us behind,
right?
Don't talk nonsense!
I'm not talking nonsense.
Our family ending up like this
is all your fault!
You indulged them!
So they've turned out like this!
Madam Tian.
Madam Tian, please calm down.
Madam Tian,
I understand how you feel.
A mother's love
for her children knows no bounds.
A mother cherishes her every child
deeply in her heart.
She cannot bear to lose any of them.
That day in court,
you must have been heartbroken.
Now that Tian Benchang has
escaped from prison to avoid punishment,
his crimes have only escalated.
And Tian Bensheng is basically dead meat.
The two of you will
also be severely punished.
Even Ronghua
can't escape punishment.
The disaster caused by one person
will drag the whole family down.
I think
this must be the worst outcome.
Bensheng, Ronghua...
Darling,
we must save Ronghua and Bensheng,
these two poor kids.
Zhen,
what exactly do you want?
Master Tian,
I know
Tian Benchang has an account book.
Is that right?
Master Tian, listen to me.
This account book
might be your Tian family's only
and last chance.
Tian Benchang managed to escape
because he used this account book
to trade for his life with Commander Wu.
But in reality,
once Commander Wu gets this account book,
he will definitely get away unscathed.
After that, he will surely
turn against your family.
In that case,
your whole Tian family
will be doomed,
with no one surviving.
Master Tian,
the only way out now
is to find Tian Benchang,
bring him to justice,
and let him confess his crimes.
Only then can this case
be completely solved.
Darling,
Zhen is right.
If you know where Benchang
has escaped to,
o-or if you know about the account book
she just mentioned,
just tell her right away.
Be honest with her now.
How could it end up like this?
Benchang said
he wouldn't abandon us.
He wouldn't abandon us?
He already fled!
You call it not abandoning us?
Darling!
Don't make any more mistakes.
Now,
you can't protect Benchang anymore.
Now, we can only try our best
to keep Bensheng
and Ronghua safe.
Our family can't fall apart, Darling.
Zhen,
I'm begging you.
Please save Ronghua.
You two are such good friends.
Madam Tian,
whether the Tian family can be saved
is not up to me now.
It's up to Master Tian.
Hurry up.
Where is it?
Inside the room.
Go.
Are you fooling me?
Do you want to die?
Where on earth is it?
Sir,
it's behind the curtain.
Behind the curtain.
It'd better be over there.
It is.
Come here.
Behave yourself.
Okay?
[Tian Family's Account Book]
Hurry.
Go.
Where is he?
Let me go!
Father,
Wensong,
thanks to Miss Li Zhen,
the Tian family has finally been
thrown into prison.
The lost souls of our Luo family
can finally rest in peace now.
You can finally get over the nightmares
that you've
suffered from all these years.
Zhen.
This is a toast to you.
From our childhood acquaintance,
to knowing each other better later,
and through all the situations
that followed,
it was all thanks to you that things
could take a turn for the better.
I'm lucky to have met you.
Thank you.
A toast to you.
Master Qi.
Luo Wenqian.
This one is for you.
Thank you for always sticking with me
through thick and thin.
No drinking.
Drinking too much
will give you a headache.
At least I don't act wildly
when I'm drunk.
Somebody
caused a scene
at our house after drinking,
made Benchang take care of him,
and kept crying and demanding
to go to the second floor.
I really didn't know
the second floor was your bedroom.
If only I had known...
Let's eat.
Let's eat up.
How silly.
Eat up.
Come on.
I made all of the dishes.
Give it a try.
Oh, right, before we eat...
Sit down first.
I want to discuss something with you.
Besides the military funds
which need to be handed in,
I still have 2,000 taels of silver.
I asked Cuiqiao to convert them
into two vouchers.
You can turn to her
whenever you're in need, okay?
You want to push me away again, don't you?
No, no.
That's not what I meant.
Even though the Tian family is in prison,
my sentence
will likely be
exile for at least 10 to 20 years.
I mean, if
I'm not around
and you ever
need money, just in case,
you can use this for emergencies.
And this rouge ink,
could you
keep it for me for the time being?
During my exile,
I don't want to affect
your happy life
for the next 10 or 20 years.
You can completely start over...
Of course, if one day
I can come back,
I will find you...
You can't take back what you've given.
Look at me. Look me in the eyes.
Luo Wenqian, listen up.
For the person I love,
not even the end of the world
could make me give in.
Whatever the verdict is tomorrow,
I will face it with you.
Understood?
Don't be sad.
It was my fault just now.
I shouldn't have said that.
Tears will mess up your face.